Crystal Yan 408.899.9671 | yan.crystal.c@gmail.com

Product management and design leader focused on transforming high-growth organizations to become more customer-centric. Experience using behavioral science and machine learning to create meaningful experiences for B2B and B2C products globally.

EXPERIENCE

Product Manager & Product Design Manager — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

MAR 2016 - PRESENT

- · Contributed to landing first enterprise client with total contract value that grew company revenue by 9% by setting vision and roadmap of a multimillion dollar product portfolio, and launching new EU, South America, and Asia product lines for web and mobile.
- Doubled product team in headcount and reduced ramp-up time for new hires by 50% by developing interviewer guides and onboarding program; report directly to COO/VP of Product.
- Designed new features and product lines that grew average contract value (ACV) 43.54% from 2015 Q4 to 2016 Q3 by leading the full-stack design discovery process (lead design sprints, conduct qualitative and quantitative user experience (UX) research with interviews and metrics analysis; lead ideation and wireframing; create interactive high-fidelity prototypes, and test with users to validate hypotheses), leading delivery sprints with engineering and QA, and planning and executing on go-to-market strategy with marketing, sales, and client success teams.

Freelance Designer & Product Strategy Consultant — Independent, Remote

AUG 2016-PRESENT

- Curriculum Design Consultant for the DC Mayor's Office Summer Youth Employment Program.
- Cofounder for Vento, LLC, a product studio launching augmented reality (AR) apps.
- UX Design Lead for MyHealthEd, Inc, a startup nonprofit transforming sex education with storytelling. Contributed to raising \$50K in funding and launching beta product by leading the UX design for an app designed for 13-14 year old low-income teens in rural areas.
- · Lead Designer for Rise, part of team that passed Survivors' Bill of Rights Act in seven state legislatures and in Congress - passed unanimously in the U.S. Senate (89-0) & U.S. House (399-0), signed by President Obama on October 7, 2016.

Associate Product Manager & UX Researcher/Designer — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2015 - MAR 2016

- · Launched company's first iOS app in four months with one engineer by producing hi-fidelity prototypes, running usability testing and beta testing, and iterating based on user feedback.
- · Aligned executive team (heads of product, sales, client success, and marketing) by developing user personas that guide product strategy, marketing campaign targeting, and sales strategy.
- · Improved site performance and remove user interface (UI) inconsistencies and lines of legacy code by developing the first style guide, UI asset and UX pattern library.

Business Development Associate — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2014 - AUG 2015

- · Contributed to company raising \$18 million in funding by consistently exceeding sales quotas and closing \$386,842 in new revenue (34% of company revenue) from new clients (Uber, Lyft, FireEye, Akin Gump, Coinbase) with shortest sales cycles, and increasing inbound leads by 36% by developing content marketing and improving SEO as interim Head of Marketing.
- Grew ACV by 76.82% by leading and developing training for 35+ new hires on optimal ways to structure pricing and contract terms in order to maximize ACV and improve cash flow.

Corporate Development Strategy — Sinovation Ventures, *Beijing, China* OCT 2012 - DEC 2013

• Diversified firm revenue by conducting analysis with recommendation to spin part of Dr. Kaifu Lee (former Google China CEO)'s VC firm's in-house UX team into an external UX studio.

Product Manager - Mobile, Standard Chartered Bank, Shanghai, China AUG 2012 - SEP 2012

- Increased inbound leads and reduced product support costs by leading product development & user testing for a bilingual (English/Mandarin) iPad app for small business owners.
- Cut development costs by 27% by analyzing vendor supplier data to identify excess expenses.

SKILLS

Management:

Interviewing, Hiring, Training, Leading **Design Sprints** User Research: Data Analysis, Contextual Inquiry, User Testing Design: Interaction, UI & Visual (Sketch, Adobe CS), Mobile, Prototyping (InVision)

SPEAKING

StarsConf Santiago Midwest UX 2017 Cincinnati SeleniumConf Berlin **Grace Hopper 2017** Orlando RubyConf Medellin **Scenic City Summit** Chattanooga **UXDC 2017** DC **ULLConf** Killarney AIGA DotGovDesign **2016** DC Microsoft Research Asia 2012 Beijing

AWARDS

McKinsey & Co. **NGWL 2017**

EDUCATION

Amherst College BA, Economics, 2014 **Tsinghua University** International Affairs Beijing, Fall 2012 **International Honors** Program Urban Planning & Anthropology Delhi, Dakar, Buenos Aires, Spring 2013